Well, we got two weeks of AI chaos
packed into one video. This week,
Microsoft and OpenAI issued a joint
statement while Microsoft was also
flirting with anthropic on the side.
Meta dropped $140 million on Black
Forest Labs to get hyperreal images. And
Photoshop is actually embracing nano
banana. Plus, Bite Dance takes a swing
at Google with Seedream. Amazon makes
everything you see shoppable. and a pro
baseball team let AI call the shots in
an actual game. There is a ton to cover
this week and I don't want to waste your
time. So, let's dive right in. Starting
with Claude's brand new abilities. You
can now create and edit files directly
within Claude. And I don't just mean
like text files or something really
basic like that. No, you can actually
create and edit Excel spreadsheets,
documents, PowerPoint slides, and PDFs
directly using Claude. At the moment,
this feature is only available in Max,
Team, and Enterprise plans. So, Pro
users that are on like the $20 a month
plan don't have it yet, but it does say
that they will get access in the coming
weeks. Now, I do have a Max plan just
because I test things on this channel
and I want to see what it can do. So,
the first thing I tested was I gave it
this PDF here. It's an OpenAI PDF called
Why Language Models Hallucinate. And
it's a big long breakdown with a lot of
confusing math and graphs and charts and
I don't totally understand it. But I
wanted to turn it into a PowerPoint
slide deck. So I literally just gave it
the PDF and said, "Turn this PDF into a
colorful slide deck." And this is what
it gave me. Not the prettiest slide deck
in the world. And Enthropic really loves
to use this like blue purple gradient
here, but this is the slide deck that it
generated for me. And you can see as I
click through it that it explains pretty
much what's going on in the paper in
slide form. Again, not the prettiest
slides you've probably ever seen, but it
definitely did it. And interestingly
enough, it says I cannot directly create
PowerPoint files. So, it turns out this
new feature, if you do have one of these
plans that it's available in, is not on
by default. So, if I come down here,
click on settings, click on features.
You can see under experimental, there's
upgraded file creation and analysis. I
need to turn this on for it to work with
Docs, spreadsheets, PDFs, etc. Now that
I have that feature turned on, it seems
like I need to create a new chat to
actually make it work. It didn't work
inside of the existing chat cuz I guess
that feature wasn't activated in that
chat. So I upload the PDF and give it
the prompt create a PowerPoint
presentation from the attached PDF. And
we can see this time it is working. I'll
create a PowerPoint presentation. And it
actually installed some like Python
libraries and is building the PowerPoint
as we watch. And after a few minutes we
have actual PowerPoint slides here. I
mean they're pretty ugly. You'd want to
go in and do some design on them
actually in PowerPoint. But we can
download them. And it looks like we can
even open them in Drive. So, if I click
this, it opens up our Google Drive. And
look, we can see it as an actual slide
deck here. So, this is where we could go
in and start designing. It actually
added a few extra bullet points that we
don't really need. Uh, so it's
definitely not the prettiest of designs,
but it did make a PowerPoint. Let's try
to get it to make an Excel spreadsheet
real quick. Make an Excel spreadsheet
that breaks down and compares the stock
prices of Nvidia, Microsoft, and Apple
over the last 12 months. So, it's
searching the web to grab all the data
for us. And it actually worked pretty
hard. You could see all of the stuff
that it did to get to this Excel
spreadsheet. And then at the end, uh, we
could see the spreadsheet that it
created for us. Not a ton of detail. Oh,
wait. Let's see. We got different tabs.
Okay. There's the detail. Nice. All
right. So, let's go ahead and open it in
Google Drive. This will be a more
accurate look at what it actually looks
like. All right. Stock price comparison
of these three companies as of September
11th, 2025, the day I'm recording this.
And then we've got our monthly price
spreadsheet and our relative performance
spreadsheet. And all of this was created
with a single prompt and it built an
Excel file for us. So pretty cool new
features coming out of Enthropic. Bummer
that it's only available on the
expensive plans right now, but it does
seem to be rolling out to the other
plans really soon. If you're a fan of
Notebook LM like I am, they rolled out
some new features for their audio
overviews. Their audio overviews is that
feature where it will make podcasts out
of whatever data you give it. Well, now
you have some additional options. You
have your default deep dive, which I
believe is kind of like the podcast we
already get. You've got a brief, which
is just a 1 to 2 minute bite-sized
overview, a critique where an expert
reviews it and offers constructive
feedback on the material, and there's a
debate mode where there's a thoughtful
debate between the two hosts. I'm pretty
sure this is available to everybody, no
matter which plan you're on. So, if I
jump into our birds aren't real notebook
that we've played with in a few past
videos, and we come up to audio overview
up here, and we click on the little pen
icon next to it, you can see we've got
our deep dive. That's the normal
conversation between the two hosts.
We've got our brief, which is a
bite-size overview, our critique, and
our debate. Let's go ahead and try a
debate. And let's generate this debate
version. And it looks like you can
generate multiple audio versions because
it's generating the normal audio
overview and I just asked it to create
the debate version and it's creating
both. And that actually took a really
long time to generate. I'd say it took
at least 5 minutes to generate our
debate, but this is what it sounds like.
Welcome to the debate. Today we're
diving into a truly fascinating online
phenomenon. Birds aren't real. I'll be
arguing that birds aren't real primarily
serves as insightful social commentary.
While I absolutely acknowledge the the
clear satirical intent behind birds
aren't real, I do believe the widespread
circulation of its content and frankly
the documented instances of literal
interpretation, they can make its
overall impact problematic.
So that's what the debate feature does.
It will make it so one AI takes one
side, the other AI takes the other side,
and then well, they debate both sides.
And again, that's just one of three new
audio overview features that you can
test out. So, jump in, throw in some
content, and maybe try the brief or the
critique and see what it does for you.
And only a couple weeks after the world
got Nano Banana, well, we got another
model out of Bite Dance from China that
claims to be the Nano Banana Killer, the
tool that's even better than Nano
Banana.
Damn.
This one is called Seeddream 4.0 or
Seedream. I think it's Seream, but
pretty much the exact same concept of
Nano Banana. You give it an image, you
tell it what you want changed about the
image, and it will make those edits. or
you give it a whole bunch of images and
tell it to sort of combine the images
and it will do that as well. And the
best way that I've found so far to use
this seed dance model is to open it in
f.ai here. It hasn't really rolled out
into most of the other platforms just
yet. So, this one seems to be the best.
And this was actually one of the
examples they gave. There was a
different person here, but they gave it
these three items of clothing and told
it to put them on that person. And I
just swapped out the person with me. I
just uploaded this image of myself and
told it to put that outfit on this
person. And this was the output I got by
giving all four of those images. Now, it
totally jacked up my face. And I promise
my legs aren't that hairy, but it put
the outfit on and the outfit looks good.
The sandals to me don't look close to
what these sandals are, but it did a
fairly decent job. Better than Nano
Banana. I don't know if I'd say that,
but maybe on par. I'm going to take
another image. I've got this image here
of when I was in New York a couple weeks
ago with the Smooth Media team and a
bunch of creators that work with Smooth
Media. And let's give it the prompt, put
this group outside at night with the New
York skyline behind them. Let's see if
it can do that for us. And it took about
22 seconds and three pennies to do, but
it did it. Just don't look too closely
at people's faces. To be fair though,
Nano Banana has the same issue. It
really jacks up people's faces,
especially when it's not like a close-up
on their face. So far from my testing,
which has been very little so far, this
model seems to be pretty much on par
with Nano Banana, but this one is taking
me 3 cents per image, where Nano Banana
I could still use for free over in AI
Studio. So, if it was me, I'm probably
still going to AI Studio for now and
using Nano Banana, but another model
that you can play around with if you
want. This new AI tool makes coding so
easy it's almost fun. And no, it's not
cursor or claw code. Warp is an identic
development environment to ship
productionready code. You just tell it
what you want to build in plain English.
It acts like an AI powered dev
assistant. But the game changer is that
you can run several agents in parallel.
One building features, another fixing
tests, another deploying, and you manage
them all in one clean panel. Here's how
I use it. Say I'm making a tweak in an
existing project. Warp shows me the
changes right in line so I can scan
through them quickly. If I need to
adjust something by hand, I can pop it
open in the editor panel and fix it
directly. I can also pull up this review
panel to easily keep track of all the
updates in one place. And the best part
is you're always in control. Warp asks
before executing anything that may be a
bit sketchy, so you can QA the generated
code and has support for MCP integration
and rules to remember all of your
preferences. I also love the smaller
features that make me prefer it over
cloud code, like the super clean UI,
ability to switch between a bunch of
support LLMs, and even voice input and
image support if you're feeling fancy.
So yeah, if you've ever wanted to make
production level coding so easy that
it's almost fun, I'd recommend giving
Warp a try. It's free and honestly might
become your new favorite dev tool. Use
the code Mattwolf to get your first
month for just $1. After that, it's just
18 bucks a month and you can cancel
anytime. Thanks so much to Warp for
sponsoring this one. Now, let's get back
to it. The company Ideog released a new
style feature. It allows you to give it
a prompt, give it a style of what you
want the image to look like, and it will
match the style of the image. You get
it. Side note, I just learned this week
from Tim over at Theoretically Media
that it's actually pronounced ideoggram.
I've been calling it idoggram this whole
time, but now I know it's ideog. But
let's try this out real quick. If I head
over to Idoggram AI, we can see we get a
giant popup introducing ideoggram
styles. Let's go ahead and try now. And
they have a whole bunch of pre-created
styles here that you can use. So, let's
say I really like this emotional minimal
style. I can select this style and you
can see it puts it down here as the
style reference. And then let's say a
man with a short brown beard holding a
microphone and waving. Just ignore these
previous images I was trying to
generate. No story there, promise. And
here we go. We got those images in that
style that we just looked at of a man
waving and holding a microphone. I mean,
they made the beard green instead of
brown, but I think that's just because
of the way that styling worked. But I
can also come up here and give it my own
style reference. Let's upload an image.
Let's give it this image as the style
reference. Why not? When the image is
uploaded, it gives us the option to edit
the image or use it as a reference. and
we'll reference the style of this image
here. I'm going to give it the prompt, a
monkey holding up a taco. And it gave me
my monkey holding a taco, but it doesn't
look like this jacked up image that I
gave it. So, it didn't quite follow the
style exactly, but it kind of followed
the color schemes, right? It didn't
follow the style, but it did match the
colors to some degree, especially the
background. The background looks like it
kind of matched the style, but that's
the ideagram new style feature. There
was also this feature that I showed off
from a couple weeks ago called realtime
video generation where you can edit an
image and in real time over on the right
side it will actually generate the video
from the image that you're currently
editing. And yes, they announced this a
few weeks ago, but they gave me access
this week so I can finally test it. I do
not know how quickly this is rolling out
or when it will be fully publicly
available. I just joined the wait list.
It took like a week and then eventually
I got an email saying, "Hey, you're in."
But this is what it looks like on the
inside. So, we've got the prompt
hyperrealistic massive white eyeball
emerging from the middle of the blue
ocean, big waves. And then on the left,
I can actually edit this. And if I move
this eyeball around, you can actually
see that my animation on the left side
changes in almost real time. There's
definitely a little bit of a delay. So,
if I move this over to the right, you'll
notice it'll take a couple seconds and
then the animation will follow. So, it's
not totally totally real time. It is
almost real time, but definitely a
little bit of a delay. And you can
create actual video animations in real
time. I don't totally know the
usefulness of this yet. It would seem
like you'd want to be able to do like
key frames, like I put the image over
here, key frame it, and then maybe move
it over here and key frame it, and then
this animation would be created based on
where I made the key frames. But it
doesn't seem like that's how it works.
It almost just kind of seems like a toy
at the moment. So, not quite sure what
to do with this yet. If you do know, let
me know in the comments right now. It's
just kind of a cool fun demo, but again,
not a lot of realworld practical use
cases that I can see yet. It's just
crazy cool. Here's another one of a
hyperrealistic 3D render of a fluffy
green monster. And you can see I can
sort of move the body around on the left
here, and it tweaks our little green
monster over on the right. Move the the
arms around, put them like way up here.
And as you can see, it animates to match
what I just did. What happens if I take
the eyes way off? Oh, my eyes just
popped off. All right. Yeah, pretty fun.
Pretty pretty pretty fun. Now, this is
one that I have no idea when this came
out, but I just discovered it this week
uh from Robin Delta here. And this is a
tool called morphic 3D motion. And it's
kind of similar to the Craya model where
you select different positions, but this
one you kind of do almost key frame them
and then it follows the animations based
on the key frames. And this one can be
accessed over at studio.mmorphic.com.
So I'm just going to start by like
pulling in a headsh shot of myself here.
So I'm going to go ahead and select this
little 3D motion icon at the top. It
brings me into this mode here. So we've
got position one, which is my starting
position of the image. But then if I
actually drag this around. Yeah, it
looks all warped and funky. But we're
basically setting the next like step. So
if I leave it there and then click on
new position, you can see it just
created position two. And then let's uh
let's do like an underneath looking up
the nose shot. And then let's do like a
crazy tweaked out looking down. Maybe
even zoom out a little bit. Call that a
new position. And then let's just submit
this as a prompt. So, I guess it's
generating our video now based on the
like four frames that I set. And well,
here's the absolutely cursed video that
I created. Yeah. Uh, it didn't quite
look like the examples I saw from uh
Robin Delta there, but it could be I
didn't give it a text prompt. So, let's
try this one more time. I'm going to add
the prompt down here. This time, the man
looks directly into the camera and see
if just making sure I give it this extra
prompt improves the output. And while I
think it got a little bit better, it's
still looking pretty cursed.
Yeah. So, not great. Don't know exactly
how uh the demos I saw looked so good.
Maybe I just had too extreme of
movements and I needed to make them more
subtle, but something fun to play around
with. I didn't spend a penny on this.
You get a certain amount of free credits
here and I've used 20 out of 100 credits
so far. So, something you can go play
around with for free. maybe you'll have
better results than I do. In the last
couple weeks, we also got a version two
from 11 Labs of their sound effects
model, which supposedly has higher sound
effects quality. And probably the cooler
feature is you can seamlessly loop sound
effects. So, I jumped into 11 Labs here,
and my producer Dave wanted to see if it
will generate the Wilhelm scream, and it
did. I just warn you, you might want to
turn down your speakers for a second
here.
And it also made three other variations.
All very similar, all very Wilhelm
screamy, but all also very loud. But
what was more interesting about this
update was the ability to loop sound
effects. So I gave it the prompt a
crackling fireplace, turned the looping
feature on, and this is what we got out
of it. And notice how it continues to
loop through. And of course, we got a
few more variations as well.
I actually like number four cuz it
sounds like they're outside with like
some crickets and stuff. But really cool
that you can make these sound effects
and make them loop as well. Now, also in
the last couple of weeks, Amazon rolled
out this Amazon Lens Live feature, which
is a feature where you can open up the
Amazon app, scan items that you see in
the real world, and it will try to find
that item or a similar item on Amazon
for you. So, let's test this out on a
couple things real quick. Let me just uh
take a few pictures. So, if I open my
Amazon app here, up by the search box,
there's a little square photo icon. And
if I press that icon, you can actually
see my camera here. All right, so let's
try this out. Sorry about the audio
quality. Let's try taking a picture of
one of my guitars here. Click our little
search. And it found the wall hooks for
the guitar, but maybe not the actual
guitar itself. Okay, there's a guitar
that looks very similar, actually. Let's
try something else. Let's look at my
camera up here. It found some Sony
cameras. Uh, just not the right one yet.
Let's see. This is a Sony ZV1 that I'm
filming on right now. And it did find
it. It's right there. The Sony Alpha
ZV1. So, it found the camera as well.
What happens if I just do like a general
area of like a bunch of stuff? So,
there's a whole bunch of things in the
shot here. Let's take a picture. What's
it going to find for us? Okay, so it
found uh like a similar cabinet to
what's back there. What about all the
junk that I have like on the shelves and
above the cabinet? It seems like it just
found the cabinet and none of the other
stuff. But a cool little app. If you're
out and about, like at a store or
something and you're like,
I kind of want that, but maybe I don't
want to buy it right now.
Go add it to your Amazon wish list by
taking a picture of it. Kind of cool.
All right. Now, that concludes the
portion of the video that I wanted to
like demo a bunch of the new stuff, but
that's not the end of the news that came
out over the last two weeks. Again, two
weeks worth of news. There's still a lot
to cover, but nothing I want to go too
deep in. So, let's go ahead and do a
rapid fire.
[Music]
I'll start by breaking down all of the
latest updates and news in large
language models. I don't like going
super deep on this anymore because most
of the updates from large language
models feel very marginal and most of
the world's probably not going to notice
huge leaps in their day-to-day use of
these models. In the last couple weeks,
Grock rolled out a new model called
Grock Code Fast 1. Back when Grock 4 was
launched, they teased a coding model
that wasn't available yet. This appears
to be that coding model. I haven't used
it myself yet. Here's some screenshots
of some code that it's generated. From
my understanding and from people I've
seen who have tested this model, most
people doing code still seem to prefer
Opus 4.1 and chat GPT03 Pro as like the
best coding models right now. But this
one does seem to be fast and cheap
compared to other models. Google rolled
out a new small model called Embedding
Gemma. This is a small open-source model
designed to be run on device. For those
that are interested, here's some
comparisons of how it compares to other
similarlysized models here. But if you
want to do a deeper dive, I will make
sure everything is linked up in the
description below. There's a new large
language model from a Swiss company
called the Swiss National Supercomputing
Center and they released a pertise which
is Latin for open. Again, not a model
I've test but another model that's
available if you want to play with it.
Alibaba released a new model called
Quinn3 Next 80B A3B.
Why? Why? It comes in two flavors. Quinn
3 next ADB A3B instruct and Quinn 3 next
ADB A3B thinking.
Here's some benchmarks for you if you
want to pause and take a look. They're
only being compared to other Quinn
models. And again, not one I've played
with a ton myself. And in the last bit
of LLM news, BYU has a new reasoning
model called Ernie X1.1.
Apparently, it's advanced in factuality,
instruction following, and agentic
capabilities, surpassing Deepseek R1,
and performing on par with models like
GPT5 and Gemini 2.5 Pro, which is really
impressive, honestly. Here's some
benchmarks where we can see the blue
line on the left of each chart. Here is
this new X1.1 model. And it seems to
beat out all the rest of the models in
accuracy, which we can see from the
Chinese Simple QA and from the BFCLV3,
which both test accuracy, as well as the
Musr. So, that seems to be the thing
that this model has going for it the
most is that it's apparently the most
accurate. It also seems to have a very
low hallucination rate compared to the
other models. We got a couple new
features inside of Chat GPT over the
last couple weeks. You can now use
projects inside of the free plan. You
can also upload more files and larger
files. You could change some of the
colors. And they added projectonly
memory controls for more tailored
context, which is something I've
absolutely wanted forever and so glad
it's in there now. They also rolled out
a new branching feature where you can
start having a chat with chat GPT. And
then if you want to jump back to a
certain spot and continue from that
spot, you can branch off and continue
the chat from that branch. Now, all
these features that I just mentioned
here, we talked about in a recent video.
I made like a starter guide, beginner's
guide to chat GPT that even if you're
kind of more intermediate to advanced,
you probably want to watch cuz I share
some really cool tips in there. But I do
talk about these new features there as
well. But just to quickly demo them, if
I open up my chat GPT account, you can
see this is what the projects feature
is. They're basically folders that let
you sort of organize various discussions
all within a single easy to access
folder here. However, you can now create
a new project. Let's say fitness coach.
And then if I click on this little cog
icon here, I can turn the memory to
project only, meaning that it will only
remember and reference things that
happened inside this folder or inside
this project. Super super helpful. It
doesn't start trying to reference chats
that you had with chat GPT outside of
the folder. It just keeps it all in one
place, which super super helpful quality
of life feature that I love that they
rolled out. And for the branching
feature, let's say you have a
conversation here and you give it a
follow-up prompt, but then maybe you
don't like the response after the
follow-up prompt and you want to jump
back and continue from this point in the
conversation instead of this point in
the conversation. Well, if I click these
little three dots here where it says
more actions, there's now a button that
says branch into new chat. If I click
that, it opens up a new chat window, but
it starts from just the first prompt and
I can continue it from here. So, another
little quality of life update from chat
GPT this week. For me, the sort of like
interplay of all of these AI companies
that are like frenemies, they work
together, they hate each other, there's
drama, all of that kind of stuff has
been some of the most fascinating things
to come out of the like AI bubble that's
happened. And this is especially
interesting. Microsoft is about to buy
AI from Anthropic. Now, if you're not
paying super close attention and you
don't know why this is interesting,
well, Microsoft owns basically 49% of
Open AI. So, the fact that they're going
to Enthropic, one of OpenAI's biggest
competitors is very interesting. But
also this week, we got this joint
statement from Microsoft and OpenAI. And
this was posted on both the Microsoft
blog and the OpenAI blog. And well, I'll
read the entire statement to you.
Microsoft and OpenAI have signed a
non-binding memorandum of understanding
or MOU. For the next phase of our
partnership, we are actively working to
finalize contractual terms in a
definitive agreement. Together, we
remain focused on delivering the best AI
tools for everyone grounded in our
shared commitment to safety. That's the
whole thing. So again, if you're not
paying attention to all the inner
workings of what's going on in the AI
world, Microsoft owns 49% of the OpenAI
sort of nonprofit umbrella. This gets
Microsoft access to OpenAI's new models
and use of OpenAI's APIs inside of the
various Microsoft tools. Well, OpenAI
wanted to shift to a nonprofit. There
was a lot of push back on that. Instead,
they shifted to a public benefit
corporation. And as they try to
restructure, well, Microsoft has been
trying to figure out where they fit in
in this whole restructuring deal. And
their joint statement this week is
basically them saying,
"We're committed to figuring out a deal
and continuing to work together."
But it also seems like Microsoft is
really pushing hard to have their own
internal models that aren't made by
OpenAI. Microsoft CEO Satia Nadella and
AI chief Mustafa Sllamon committed to
significant investments in its own
models. We should have the capacity to
build world-class frontier models
inhouse of all sizes, but we should be
very pragmatic and use other models
where we need to, said Solomon.
Apparently, the nonprofit parent
company, the OpenAI nonprofit, will
continue to hold authority over the
for-profit business with an equity stake
worth more than a hundred billion. So,
the nonprofit that Microsoft has their
interest in will still kind of have
control over whatever new OpenAI
structure happens. And since we're
talking about companies working together
and all of these overlaps and things
like that, well, it turns out Meta is
going to pay $140 million to use Black
Forest Labs for AI images. Now, a couple
weeks ago, we talked about how Meta is
partnering with Midjourney for image
generation. Well, Black Forest Labs is
like a direct competitor to Midjourney.
They're both their own separate image
generation models. So, why the heck
would Meta go and invest in working with
Midjourney and go and invest in Black
Forest Labs when both of them can
generate AI images? My guess, I'm not
saying this is totally accurate, but my
guess is that Black Forest Labs is
really good at creating ultra realistic
images that are almost indistinguishable
from real images, where MidJourney has
more of like an aesthetic, right? You
could look at a MidJourney image and
kind of tell that was probably made with
MidJourney. like it has a a stylized
look to it. So my guess is that Meta
wants both sides. They want Black Forest
Labs for the ultra realism. They want
Midjourney because Midjourney is a
wellrespected brand and AI image
generation. And also they've got that
aesthetic that a lot of people really
like. This week was also the annual
Apple event where they launched their
new iPhone and other gadgets. And they
did debut a new iPhone 17. They also
debuted like an Air version that's a lot
thinner. They introduced some new
versions of the Apple Watch, which I
believe has like some AI health coach
kind of stuff in it. And they introduced
the new AirPods Pro 3. And for me, this
was the biggest release from the whole
event. The AirPods Pro 3 look really,
really impressive because, well, they've
got new active noise cancellation, which
sounds really, really good. They've got
a new heart rate sensor for working out.
But the absolute coolest feature is the
live translation built directly into the
AirPods with AirPods Pro 3. Live
translation enables in-person
communication across select languages
and is available in beta. So just check
out the little demo video. This is
pretty cool.
Hello. Welcome. Today all the red
carnations are 50% off. I'd love to take
some of these to my sister for her
birthday. I'll buy eight, please. And
then when you respond to the person, you
just hold up your phone and whatever
you're saying in English translates to
their native language and they can just
read it off of your phone.
Did you understand a word of that?
Our universal translators must be
malfunctioning.
And what's even cooler is if both
parties have these AirPod 3s in, they
can each speak in their natural language
and hear in their natural language.
I agree. Yeah.
Let's
definitely the client will love that.
I'll let the strategy team know to
prepare that immediately.
That to me is absolutely gamechanging.
We're entering into a world where
communication and languages are no
longer a barrier. And it's only a matter
of time before everyone pretty much has
some sort of earbuds that translate
because the Google buds, I think,
already do this. We're getting it in
AirPods pretty soon. This is just going
to be a standard thing and everybody's
going to have headphones that translate
with anybody. And that's a world I'm
pretty excited about. Speaking of
translation, Google just rolled out a
new circle to search feature that will
translate anything you see on your
screen. So, in their examples here, you
can see they take a picture and then
they have it automatically translate
whatever is going on in the picture. So,
look at this bag. It shows you exactly
what the bag says and it's pretty cool
looking. One thing I do find a little
interesting though is it says this
update will begin rolling out this week
on Android starting with select Samsung
Galaxy devices. And that makes no sense
to me that they roll it out for Samsung
Galaxy devices because Google owns the
Google Pixel. Like this is their Android
phone. Why aren't they rolling it out in
the phones that they create? Why does
this stuff come out on Galaxy's first? I
mean, I'm sure it's some sort of
contractual thing, but damn it, I've got
a Google Pixel here, and I want to test
this feature out. There's some minor new
updates with VO3 as well. You can now
generate vertical videos directly with
V3. They also reduce the cost by quite a
bit. VO3 almost got cut in half and V3
fast got cut by more than half. And
well, if V3 is rolling out vertical
videos, we know what that means. It's
probably coming to YouTube shorts very,
very soon. In fact, YouTube has already
confirmed that it's coming to YouTube
shorts. Back at Can's Lions this year,
Neil Mohan, the CEO of YouTube, did say
YouTube is bringing its V3 AI video
generation model to YouTube Shorts later
this summer. And I mean, summer's almost
over, so it'll probably be in YouTube
Shorts pretty damn soon. V3 is also
available inside of Google Photos where
you can take any of your photos inside
of Google Photos and animate them. For
some reason, the Google Photos app
doesn't let me share my phone screen
with you. But if you look at my phone
here, you can see the little create
button down in the bottom menu. And if
you click create, you can see there's a
phototovideo feature there that will
turn whatever photos you have in Google
Photos into video using VO3. If you're a
fan of Nano Banana, well, you can use
Nano Banana now directly inside of
Leonardo. It's pretty simple. Go to the
image section inside of Leonardo. Click
on one of the images that you recently
generated. And then down in the bottom
where you select your model. You can see
you have the option for Flux one context
GPT1 and nano banana. Go ahead and
select nano banana and say put a shirt
on the alien that says future tools. And
within seconds I have my updated image
that used nano banana. And since we're
talking about nano banana, it turns out
that Adobe Photoshop's just embracing
it. We've seen all sorts of video titles
and XT threads and things like that
saying Photoshop is dead. Well, it turns
out no. Photoshop is just going to
leverage Nano Banana. According to my
friend Chris Castanova here, who works
at Adobe, Nano Banana is coming to
Photoshop natively. You'll be able to
actually select Nano Banana as one of
the models. I don't know when it's
rolling out exactly, but we do know Nano
Banana is going to be directly inside of
Photoshop soon. This is an interesting
story that comes out of an absolutely
heartbreaking scenario, but I feel like
I need to share this as like a sort of
public interest sort of thing. So, as we
all know, Charlie Kirk, the political
commentator, was assassinated, and
people are trying to use AI to upscale
images of the suspect. Right? So, these
are the original images that the FBI
shared right here. And you can see
they're pretty low res, grainy images.
And what people have been doing is
tossing these images into upscalers and
saying, "Look, I upscaled the image for
you, so now we know what this guy looks
like." That's not how the upscalers
work. This is not necessarily how the
guy looks. When you plug in an image
into an upscaler, what the upscaler is
doing is it's using AI to guess what
those extra pixels in between the pixels
it knows about are. So, when you have a
very grainy image that looks very
pixelated and you try to upscale it, AI
is going to add a whole bunch of new
pixels in there to try to sharpen the
image, but it's making its best guess at
what it thinks those pixels should be to
create the image. And you'll notice
there's three upscaled images here and
they look like three different people.
So, don't believe that upscaling low-res
images is a way to see a better quality
version and try to get more details out
of the image because the details are
hallucinated. They're not necessarily
real details. And that doesn't go for
just this one story alone. It's probably
something that's just good to know about
AI. All right, now let's move into some
of the final like fun stories of this
week. a baseball team this week out of
Oakland called the Oakland Ballers were
the first team to let AI manage the
game. So, this team, the Oakland
Ballers, their manager, Aaron Miles,
created a little AI tool that decided
the lineup of the game, who should be
pitching, when to pull the pitcher, when
to put in pinch hitters, pinch runners,
things like that. Basically, decide all
of the management of the game. They let
AI make every single decision. And in
the game where they tested this, they
actually won. So, the AI did a good job.
You son of a
If you're into autonomous vehicles, the
company Zuks, which is owned by Amazon,
is getting ready to launch their robo
taxis in Las Vegas. And this is what the
robo taxis look like. I actually saw
them in person at CES this year. And
they're more like a robo bus. It's like
a little mini bus that you get in and
sit down in. Doesn't even have a
steering wheel or gas pedal or anything.
You just get in and sit down and it is
going to shuttle people up and down the
strip and could be a pretty strong
contender against Elon's tunnel thing
that goes underneath Vegas, the
Hyperloop. Cuz the Hyperloop really only
goes between like the convention center
and like one hotel and these little Zuks
buses will be able to shuttle you up and
down the strip and will probably be
quite a bit more convenient. Next time
I'm in Vegas, I'm definitely going to
give it a try. And in this week's
edition of Can AI do the stuff that I
really don't want to do myself, we got a
humanoid robot that can do your dishes
for you. Now, this is the figure robot,
and we previously saw this robot putting
laundry into a washing machine. We saw
it folding laundry, and now we see it
doing our dishes. And this is the world
that everybody wants robots to do for
them. Do my dishes, do my laundry, clean
up after me, make my food. That's the
kind of stuff we want our AI robots to
do. So, we could be lazy and be those
fat people sitting in the wall-ally
chairs just watching TV and drinking
slurpees all day. And well, we're
finally getting the robots that are
going to help us achieve that utopia.
But that's what I got for you today.
This was 2 weeks worth of news, so this
video is probably slightly longer than
my normal news videos, but there was a
lot to cover. I'm going to be in New
York again coming up here. And so my
next news video might be on location
from New York. Assuming there's enough
interesting news to talk about that
week, which there will be because we
have both Meta Connect and the made on
YouTube events coming up. There's going
to be plenty of news to talk about next
week. But again, I covered everything
from the last two weeks that I thought
you would find interesting. My job is to
keep my finger on the pulse of
everything that's happening in AI, to
test stuff, to demo it, to tell you all
about the news so that just once a week
you can be fully looped in with these
videos. if you want. Hopefully I
achieved that goal this week for you and
you feel more looped in. And if you do
want to make sure you always feel very
looped in on this insanely fastm moving
industry, make sure you like this video
and subscribe to this channel. It will
make sure more videos like this news
roundup show up for you, as well as some
really cool AI tutorials on how to do
awesome stuff using these tools. Again,
just like, subscribe, do all the things.
It's much much appreciated, and I will
keep on trying to be as helpful as
possible for you. I really really
appreciate you tuning in, nerding out,
spending time with me. It means the
world to me that I get to do this. So,
thank you so so much. I really, really
appreciate you. And hopefully I'll see
you in the next one. Bye-bye. Thank you
so much for nerding out with me today.
If you like videos like this, make sure
to give it a thumbs up and subscribe to
this channel. I'll make sure more videos
like this show up in your YouTube feed.
And if you haven't already, check out
futuretools.io where I share all the
coolest AI tools and all the latest AI
news. And there's an awesome free
newsletter. Thanks again. really
appreciate you.